I've got a right angled triangle having
happiness 10 centimeters side B is 8
centimeters and side C is six
centimeters we are going to prove the
Pythagoras Theorem so in five seconds
theorem we are to prove that hypotenuse
10 centimeter square is equal to the sum
of 6 centimeters square and eight
centimeter Square so let's prove the
bicycle theorem I have got four copies
of this trendal ADC we are going to plot
these four triangles in this Square p q
r s Having side 14 centimeters so first
we are going to create the square on the
hypotenuse so you can see that by using
the four copies of the triangle ABC we
have created a white square inside 10
centimeters that is the hypotenuse of
the triangle ABC area of this y Square
hundred centimeter Square now let's
prove the another part of the particular
theorem so this is the second part of
the particular theorem here we have b
square is 6 into 6 is 36 centimeter
centimeter Square whereas the other
white part is 8 into 1864 64 square
centimeters we see that 64 plus 36 is
100 square centimeters so uh before we
have 100 square centimeters as C square
and now we have 64 plus 36 that is 100
square centimeters as b square plus C
Square so a square equals to b square
plus C square and hence Pythagoras
Theorem is proved